这小老弟从我家门口偷拿快递，现在他想在车里拆开它
This guy took a package from my porch and now he's about to open it in his car
但他没想到这快递是我特制的诱饵，能从四个方向录像
But what he doesn't know is this is a custom-built bait package that is recording him on four different cameras
它还会释放出一斤左右的世界上最绚丽的亮片外加一些别的惊喜
And it's about to unleash a pound of the world's finest glitter along with some other surprises.
但要知道他造了什么孽，我们还得从头说起
But to understand how he got to this point first. We need to rewind a bit.
七个月前我的一个快递说已派送，但我却没收到
About seven months ago, I noticed a package being reported as delivered but it never arrived.
然后我看了下家里监控，看到了这对正在散步的甜美两口子
So when I checked our security cameras, I noticed this lovely couple out for a stroll.
如你所见，他们背着个包在街坊闲逛，打发下午的时光
As you can see, they have backpacks on and they're just going around the neighborhood making an afternoon out of this.
你如果经历过这种事情，就会感觉我有多来气
If you ever been in a situation like this, you just sort of feel violated.
然后我拿着录像证据去找警察叔叔
And then I took this to the police and even with the video evidence,
他们说不想浪费时间查此事——就感觉很无助
they said it's just not worth their time to look into -  so then you also feel powerless
我觉得我应该做点什么，好好给那些人上一课
and I just felt like something needs to be done to take a stand against dishonest punks like this.
我当时灵光一闪：我能造一个自动让飞镖命中靶心的可移动靶
And then I was like: hold up, I built a dartboard that moves to get a bulls-eye every time.
我花了九年时间设计的硬件正在另一个星球的探测车上运行
I spent nine years designing hardware that's currently roving around on another freaking planet.
如果谁能利用这些技术造一个用来复仇的诱饵快递包裹
If anyone was going to make a revenge bait package and over-engineer the crap out of it,
那这人非我莫属
it was going to be me.
然后打开Sketch和CAD
So I started with a Sketch and some CAD
叫上我一个擅长做这些小电子玩意的朋友Sean开始干活
and then I hit up my buddy Sean who is really good with this type of small electronic stuff and we got to work.
最终效果就是，当小偷打开包裹的时候
Ultimately, when they open the package
我想让他们看到我对他们聪明绝顶的祝贺，所以我用到了小亮片
I just wanted to celebrate their choice of profession with a cloud of glitter
谁不喜欢小亮片呢~
because, I mean, who doesn't love glitter?
这很好做到，里面放个弹簧就行了
That's easy. I could just do that passively with like a spring when it opens
但我还想录下来他们的反应，这就需要点技术了
But I also wanted to record their reaction and that's what makes the engineering here an order of magnitude more difficult.
你想，这玩意要放地上一整天，还不能插着插头
Because if you think about it This thing has to sit on a porch all day and it can't be plugged in
你也不知道小偷啥时候会来偷
and you have no idea when someone will come and pick this up.
所以你不能单纯按下录像键后放进盒子里
So it's not like you could just hit record on the camera and then put it in the box
因为电和存储空间会很快耗尽
because you're gonna run out of battery and storage space on top of that.
我需要一些方法让我能重新拿回录像和包裹
I need some way to recover this footage in case I never get the big package back
所以经过半年的设计与测试，最终产品是这样的
so after six months and lots of design Iterations and so much testing here's where we landed
这个定制的电路板是所有操作的大脑
This custom printed circuit board is the brains of the operation
内含加速度传感器
It has a built-in accelerometer
当其感应到晃动时，它会检查GPS信号，判断自己是否已经离开家门
And when it's jostle that will check the GPS signal to see if it's been moved from the porch.
如果是的话，它会唤醒所有手机开始记录
And if so it sends a signal to all the phones to wake up and start recording.
我使用了四台带有广角录像模式的手机，并在盒子内向后倾斜
And I'm using four phones that have a wide-angle filming mode and are angled back
3D打印的外壳与手机如图所示，红色为相机的视野
and this 3d printed portion is contoured this way because it represents the field of view of the phones
如你所见，这样小偷无论从哪个方向打开盒子都能录下来他们的反应了
So as you can see I'm guaranteed to capture their reaction no matter which way they open it from.
里面还有一个臭屁喷雾，不开玩笑，这一小瓶能让整个房间寸草不生
And nestled in here we've got a can of fart spray. No joke, you can clear a room with one spray of this stuff.
上面放置一个小电机，连接一个凸轮，每30秒喷5次
so we made a cam on a small motor that sprays it five times
这设计不止是作为亮片的修饰
and not only is this just a nice touch
还有个目的是要让他们在发现里面有四个手机之前把包裹扔出车外或者房子外
but we keep repeating five sprays every 30 seconds until they throw the package out of their car or house
before they realize there's four phones inside.
这会提高我们找到它的概率，因为我们装了GPS，可随之知晓其位置
This increases our chances of finding it because we always know the package location at all times due to the GPS on the phones
但万一我们没找回它，四台手机还装有4G数据卡
But even if we don't recover it, all four phones have LTE data plans.
它们可以把影响上传至云端，我仍然可以下载回来
So they upload the footage to the cloud so I can still see what happened
而最大的亮点是我在顶上放了个能旋转的碗
pièce de résistance: referring to the best part or feature of something
（法语，指某物最棒的一部分或特点）
And then for the pièce de résistance we have a cup here on top that spins from a motor underneath.
当你在里面装满世界上最好看的小亮片
So once you load in a but ton of the world's finest glitter,
下面电机的高速旋转会让亮片向四面八方飞出去
the motor spins really fast and the centrifugal force fires it evenly in all directions.
再在外包装上打两个孔，贴好单向透明纸
Let me cut holes on the side of the lid and cover them with one-way film
这样其中两个相机就能在他们离开的时候看到他们
so two of the cameras can see them as they walked away.
最后为了让它像真正的快递包裹
And then finally to make it look like an actual delivered package
我们在外面塑封好，并贴好运单
we added some shrink wrap and a delivery label
上面有我最得意的彩蛋
which is perhaps my favorite part of the whole thing
如果小偷稍微留意看一眼的话
because if the thief wasn't in such a hurry
他们会发现这个包裹来自我童年心目中的英雄
they'd see that the package is actually coming from my childhood hero
他也为我整个计划提供了灵感，这个人就是Kevin McCallister
and inspiration for this project Kevin McCallister.
我还特意查了下这电影里的房子在哪
I even looked up and amusing the address of the actual house they filmed the movie in
暗示偷快递的就像这俩笨贼一样
收件人也写的两个笨贼的名字——“Harry and Marv”
and of course it's being shipped to his boys Harry and Marv.
底部还有个充电口，万一在外面放置一段时间后还没被偷
And there's a charge port in the bottom because if it doesn't get stolen in a given day.
我可以把它拿回来充满电再放回去
I can bring it in and then recharge all the batteries in the system overnight.
想法就是这样，坏蛋来到门口拿走快递
So the idea is the bad guy comes and takes it off your porch
然后打开盒子，触发两个开关
then lifts the lid and these two limit switches
内部电路得知盒盖已被拿开，并启动所有内部装置
tell the circuit board brain inside that the lids been removed and then that sets everything in motion.
或许是我的偏见吧，但有时一个精心的设计真的很酷炫！
And I may be biased but sometimes a well engineered design is beautiful.
因为电话有GPS功能，所以我在我家周围弄了一个虚拟地理围栏
And because the phones have GPS we created a virtual geo fence around my house
当包裹位置离开我家的时候我就会收到通知
so I get a notification when the package has been moved off the property.
然后我把盒子放到家门口，然后就是漫长的等待了
So I put it out on the porch and now all that was left to do was wait.
OK，我正上班呢收到通知说盒子离开虚拟地理围栏了
Okay, so I was at work and I got a notification that the Geo fence we set up had been tripped.
我检查了下监控画面并确认包裹的确被拿走了
So then I checked the cameras and sure enough. The package is gone.
我打开GPS追踪了一下
So I checked the GPS and sort of tracked it,
貌似包裹在一辆车里，因为它离开我家的速度挺快的
and it appears there in a car because they seem to leave my house pretty quickly.
最后好像进了一个停车场，我现在正在前往那里
But it seems to have stopped in a parking garage which is where I'm headed to now.
如果你是第一次看我的频道，我先说好我这频道不是专门搞恶作剧的
And if you're new here, this isn't a prank channel.
所以我现在真挺不习惯的
So I am completely out of my comfort zone.
喔它在那
And there she is.
就好像从失事飞机上取回黑匣子一样
This is like recovering the black box of a crashed airplane.
当然即使我没找到也没问题
It would still work even if I didn't get the box back.
录像内容会被上传到云端，但我把它插回电脑会更快一点
That footage would upload to the cloud but it's just faster to plug the phones in
所以我们回家看看它到底经历了什么
so I'm gonna go home and find out how this Somehow ended up here.
监控显示这人在人行道上突然左转
So it appears he was walking down the sidewalk and then suddenly makes a hard left.
拿走包裹上车走人最后开到这个停车场
Then he takes the package and gets in his car and eventually makes it to this parking garage
接下来就是见证奇迹的时刻
where this glorious sequence unfolds.
录像里的英语很简单啦 就不翻译了
但请务必调小音量！！！
这个故事告诉我们，不可以拿别人的东西
So the moral of the story is just don't take other people's stuff
这一点不酷，而且你永远不会知道等待你的是这种下场
Not only is it not cool, but on the plus side, you'll never find yourself in this situation
甚至更糟，比如下面这段
or perhaps even worse this one.
字幕翻译给虫 欢迎点赞投币收藏转发分享关注充电评论